Daniel French

College Station, TX | 832.316.7138 | dan.r.french@sbcglobal.net | LinkedIn

Summary

I have a passion for learning, solving problems and analyzing information. I have professional experience building and managing responsive client websites using WordPress, as well as creating child themes to modify theme plugins. I also have a solid understanding of object-oriented programming with C#.

Experience

Centennial Arts | Software Developer

January 2024 - Present

- Designed and built customer websites using WordPress
- Installed and managed WordPress packages and plugins on FreeBSD operating system
- Logged and communicated progress on customer websites and other issues using Jira
- Created child themes to modify theme plugin files
- Curated plugins for situational use
- Documented new processes in Confluence for collecting website content, plugin setup and usage, child theme directory structure and usage, and managing core WordPress settings

Real Estate Agent | Keller Williams Realty Brazos Valley

April 2021 – October 2023

- Marketed our services through social media, direct mail campaigns and outbound phone calls
- Prepared and presented pricing analyses and marketing strategies to prospective listing clients
- Showed properties to prospective buyers
- Maintained transaction paperwork such as contract addenda, listing agreements, buyer's representation agreements, etc.

Courier | FedEx Express

October 2010 - April 2023

- Responsible for safely and efficiently sorting and delivering packages in College Station and surrounding areas
- Led the team responsible for receiving and delivering First Overnight packages
- Supervised unloading activities and ensured a successful flow rate of packages per hour

Education

True Coders Full Stack Software Engineering Program

Graduated July 2023

- Project based training in programming languages and other technical skills, such as SQL,
 C#, .NET Core, Git ASP.NET MVC, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Skills were developed by building multiple C# and SQL projects in Visual and Visual Studio Code
- C# and SQL Projects were tracked in Git and GitHub for source control
- Managed SQL databases using CRUD operations in MySQL

B.B.A in Marketing, Texas A&M University-Kingsville

Graduated December 2008

- Gained a solid foundation in marketing principles such as market research, consumer behavior and market segmentation
- Learned personal sales skills and techniques
- Learned strategies for market entry and analyzing strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats in competitive markets
- Accounting Principles
- Graduated with honors (3.6 G.P.A.)

Skills & abilities

- WordPress
- HTML
- CSS
- MySQL
- C#

Links

- LinkedIn
- GitHub
- Portfolio